Hello everyone, I am Liu Yian from the Department of CCEP at National Cheng Kung University.
Today I will be introducing the project I have been working on in this semester in the department.
The focus of my project is related to stock market trending.
This project is closely related to data science methods.
Due to time constraints,you can find more detailed information on the data craft explorer channel.
The specifics will be provided in the description below.
Interested friends are welcome to check it out.
While engaging in stock market operations,I noticed three commonly used methods for prediction and trading.
I began contemplating the idea of combining these three methods to potentially achieve better trending returns.
This led to the development of my project.
The content of my presentation today follows the structure from top to bottom and indicated by the gray and blue boxes.
Let's dive into it.
Since my final project poster is quite lengthy,I'll divide the introduction into two parts.
Starting with the blue box on the right,I obtained test data for popular target among young investors.
Taiwan Yuan Da Wushu,005 Liro,and ETF encompassing the top 50 companies in Taiwan.
Due to its representation of the overall economy growth in Taiwan,it's a favorite investment trace.
The data used spans from January 2014 to November 2023,and includes daily trending information such as closing and opening prices,daly highs,lowes,trending volume,and percentage price changes compared to the previous day.
I transformed this data into a turn chart,as seen in the rightmost white chart.
The overall term suggests an upward trajectory.
Now,let's live into three common stock market trending strategies I exploited.
The first one is golden core strategy.Premily based on moving average.
Flooming average is a point that among the past 20 day stock price average is today's point,and we create a line in the chart.
So,I chose a 20 day long term moving average and 5 day short term moving average.
The intersection of this average serves as an entry and is it praying for trading.
The initial result over 10 year period from 2014 to 2023,yielding a total return rate of 62.48%.
Demonstrating favorable trending outcomes.
The second strategy on the bottom is a random forest,a machine learning method that uses past data predict future stock prices.
The result shows an impressive accuracy with an R2 score of 0.999,indicating highly precise prediction.
By the way,the lowest accuracy of R2 score is 0 and the highest is 1,so that 0.999 which is really high.
And the predict and actual price is at the chart in the most left button.
You can see that this two line is very close,so that you think it is only a one line.
And which shows that the predict result is very close to the actual price.
Ok,the third strategy involves long short term memory,which as known as LSTM,which unlike random forest,
consider only historical data for predicting stock prices,while slightly less accurate than random forest with an R2 score of 0.95.
Again,the lowest accuracy for R2 score is 0,and the highest is 1.
So LSTM still demonstrate good predictive capabilities.
Moving on to the integration of these strategies at the blue block,I explore combining the golden core strategy with LSTM and random forest.
The cumulative returns from these combined strategies were analyzed,revealing interesting insights.
Golden core contributed possibility,while LSTM show unexpected negative return,which is at the last row.
You can see that the golden core return is 4.5,and LSTM return is -2.5.
Random forest return is 3.7.
This discrepancy might be attributed to the specific time interval chosen for the analysis.
So in conclusion,the future work involves testing these strategies across different time intervals to obtain a comprehensive understanding of their effectiveness.
This project provides a foundation of potential improvements in trending accounts by integrating various prediction methods.
So this is all of my content. Thank you for your attention.